Guide to the Marilyn Symmes Collection of Art Exhibition Ephemera 1973-2019 (bulk 1990s-2019) PR 352
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Multiple Artists Exhibitions, 1992-2016
  - Y-Z, 2005-2015 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 10)
    Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: The Yale University Art Gallery, The Zimmerli Art Museum at Rutgers University, Zwirner & Wirth Gallery, and Zwirner Gallery.
  - S-Z (Set 2), 1988-2018 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 13)
    Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: Segura Arts Studio Notre Dame Center for Arts & Culture, Smithsonian Cooper-Hewitt National Design Museum, The Steelcase Design Partnership, 'T' Space, Tang Museum at Skidmore College, University of Pennsylvania Graduate School of Fine Arts and Annenberg Public Policy Center, Wallach Art Gallery at Columbia University, The Walther Collection, Washburn Gallery, Whitney Museum of American Art, and Zabriskie Gallery.
  - Oversize, 1999-2015 (Folder FF-1)
    Includes: Posters exhibition (1999) at Lawrence Markey; The Downtown Show: The New York Art Scene, 1974-1984 (2006) at Grey Art Gallery & Fales Library, NYU (brochure); Protest (2003) and Do (2004) at Pace/MacGill Gallery; Tumescence (2013) and Body Shop (2015) at Michael Werner; Untragbar: Mode als Skulptur (2001) at Museum fur Angewandte Kunst Koln.
- Series IV. Architecture & New York City-related Exhibitions, 1991-2018
  The series holds items pertaining to exhibitions related to architecture and/or New York City. The category includes all those items so designated by the collector/donor. By the donor's count, there are about 37 items in the series.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged alphabetically by gallery/exhibition venue.
  - A-M, 2000-2018 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 14)
    Includes material from architectural and New York City related shows and programs at the following museums, spaces, and galleries: Alliance for Downtown New York, Inc., Architectural League of New York, Architekturzentrum Wien, Arquitectonica: The Times Square Project, Brasserie Americaine, Franklin D. Roosevelt Four Freedoms Park, International Print Center New York, The Jewish Museum, Keith De Lellis Gallery, Kitchen Club, Max Protetch, and The Museum of Contemporary Art, Los Angeles. Also includes a pamphlet from The Jewish Museum that features questions and answers from the designers, Stefan Sagmeister and Jessica Walsh, on their exhibition, "Six Things", and includes a brief biography. Also includes a brochure from MOCA at the Geffen Contemporary on its exhibition, "At the End of the Century: 100 Years of Architecture" with an insert on another exhibition, "The Unbuilt".
  - N-Z, 1991-2017 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 15)
    Includes material from architectural and New York City related shows and programs at the following museums, spaces, and galleries: National Academy Museum & School, National Building Museum, The Odeon, PaineWebber Art Gallery, The Queens Museum, The Skyscraper Museum, SITE, Smithsonian Cooper-Hewitt, National Design Museum, Spoleto Festival U.S.A. (Charleston), University of Michigan Museum of Art, The Wallach Art Gallery, and Yale School of Architecture. Also includes National Building Museum brochures from its exhibitions, "On the Job: Design and the American Office (2000)", "On Track: Transit and the American City (2002)", and "The Turner City Collection: Rendering a Century of Building (2002)". Includes information sheets from the Queens Museum on its exhibitions: "The Panorama of the City of New York". "Relief Map of New York City's Watershed", "The Marvel of New York City's Water Supply System", and "Never Built New York". Includes reprints and information on SITE. Includes information on the Cooper-Hewitt's exhibitions, "Masterpieces from the Vitra Design Museum: Furnishing the Modern Era (2000)", "Aluminium by Design: Jewelry to Jets (2001)", and "New Hotels for Global Nomads (2002)". Includes a program from Spoleto Festival U.S.A. on its exhibition, "Places with a Past: New Site-Specific Art in Charleston". Includes a Yale University brochure on its exhibition, "Pedagogy and Place: Celebrating 100 Years of Architecture Education at Yale".
- Series V. Holiday Greeting Cards, Invitations & Miscellaneous Posters, 2000-2018, undated
  The series includes exhibition announcements that take the form of invitations to openings, a few holiday cards, and some miscellaneous prints, posters and other material not related to art exhibitions. The latter miscellany are listed by item in the container list.
  The subseries is arranged by document type.
  - Holiday Greeting Cards, 2000-2018, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 16)
    Includes cards from American Academy in Rome, Antonio Fransconi, Emilio Sanchez Foundation, Larissa Goldston Gallery, Lower East Side Printshop, The Metropolitan Museum of Art, Mixed Greens Gallery (includes a print (513/1250) of a drawing, signed by artist Leah Tinori), Terra Foundation for American Art, and Universal Limited Art Editions.
  - Invitations - ArtTable, 1996-2019 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 17)
    Includes invitations to ArtTable Award programs from 1996, 1997, 2003, 2010, 2011, 2012, 2017, 2018, and 2019.
  - Invitations - IPCNY, 2013-2019 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 18)
    Includes invitations to the International Print Center New York (IPCNY) Spring Benefit for years 2013, 2016, 2017, 2018, and 2019.
  - Invitations - Michael Werner, 2008-2019 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 19)
    Includes invitations to exhibitions at the Michael Werner Gallery in New York and in London.
  - Invitations A-Z, 1997-2000, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 20)
    Includes invitations to exhibitions, benefits, dinners, and ceremonies from The American Academy of Arts and Letters, American Friends of the British Museum, The American Institute of Architects New York Chapter, The Art Show, Associates of the Art Commission, Cantor Arts Center at Stanford, The Ciesla Foundation, the Civil Rights Memorial Center, Dieu Donne Papermill, The Drawing Center, The Frick Collection, International Center of Photography, The Metropolitan Museum of Art, The Morgan Library, The Noguchi Center, The Pace Gallery, Robert Miller Gallery (opening), Smithsonian Cooper-Hewitt, National Design Museum, Society of Architectural Historians, and The UBS Art Gallery.
  - Print. "A special excerpt from 'The Cottage' by Valerie Duncan", 2017 (Offsite-box 22)
    "Printed for members of the Print Council of America on occasion of their visit to Maine Media Workshops and College, May 4, 2017"
  - Print. Linotype Lunar Calendar, 2018 (Offsite-box 22)
    Printed by DWRI Letterpress, Providence RI.
  - Screenprint. "Here" by Grace Paley, 2006 (Folder FF-5)
    Design & letterpress printing by Roni Gross. Signed on verso "Roni Gross." Verson reads: "One hundred copies of this broadside were printed in honor of the author's reading at the Center for Book Arts, New York City, April 28, 2006." On front: is poem by Paley, signed in ink lower right "Grace Paley"; 12 11/16 x 12 3/8"
  - Booklet of postcards. "Paul Robeson: The Journey of a Renaissance Man", 2003 (Offsite-box 22)
    Printed by Pomegranite, San Francisco. Introduction and compilation by Paul Robeson Jr, with images from the Robeson family collection.
  - Poster. "Urban Open Spaces", undated (Folder FF-5)
    Image of Manhattan street grid with identification of various types of open spaces in the built environment.
  - Poster. "Hillary 16", 2016 (Folder FF-5)
    Individual images of all U.S. presidents through Barack Obama and ending with a photo of Hillary Clinton.